Good afternoon everyone
大家下午好
So today we're going to transition into a topic that
今天我们将过渡到一个新的章节
To me is sort of the reward for having slugged through all the low-level stuff you've done up to this point
对我来说,这是看完你们到目前为止完成的所有低级作业的奖励
To be able to really understand and become adept at programming network software
这个章节中，我们的目标是能真正地理解和熟练地编写网络软件
Now there's a lot to networking that we're not going to cover
现阶段,有很多关于网络设计的内容我们不准备涵盖
But at least to have some familiarity with it
但至少应对它有点熟悉
So I know that a lot of you are sort of in the midst of trying to figure out
我知道你们中很多人还沉浸在找出
How to make malloc run and make it run fast
让储存管理器运行更快的方法
And so this topic is really more pointing toward the future
然而这个章节在长远来看更重要
But it's very relevant to the final web lab you'll do for the course
它和你们将要在这个课程中完成的期末网络实验关系很大
And so we're starting to get ready for that
所以我们现在就开始为它做准备吧
So like I said this course is not really a full course in networking
就像我说的,这门课程并不是一门完整的网络设计课程
There's many other courses at the university that are
在大学期间还有很多其他课程(与网络设计有关)
And so what we're going to try and do is give you just a little flavor of it
所以我将要做的只是让你们对它有一定的了解
And particularly as everything in the course of programmers perspective
就像我们在这15-213门课的大部分时间做的事情一样
So how you as a software developer would make use of the C level api's that are relevant to network programming
那么,作为一名程序员，你们准备怎样利用与网络编程有关的 C 语言的 api
And why isn't this working
它为什么不灵了
Okay so
好的，那么
The idea behind most networking systems is what's called  the client-server model
大多数网络系统都是基于客户端-服务器模型编写的
And the idea is that there's a service out there that you want access to
主要的思路就你想要使用某项服务
And you as a customer or a client are making a request to that server
然后客户端对那台服务器发出一个请求
So an example would be when you order something on amazon
举个例子，当你在亚马逊上订购一些东西时
Amazon has a bunch of servers
亚马逊有一些服务器群
And you go to your web browser and contacts the amazon a web server
你通过浏览器和亚马逊的一台网络服务器通信
And you make transactions you request something you provide information
比如做一些交易，查找一些东西，或是提供一些信息
And it gives you back pretty pictures of things you might want to buy
然后它给了你一些你可能想要买的东西的精美图片
It acknowledges your credit card transactions
交易通过你的信用卡完成
Those are all very classic client-server types of interactions
这就是很经典的客户端-服务器型互动
You as the client,amazon is the server
你这边是客户端，亚马逊那边就是服务器
Another interesting example is a telephone
另一个有趣的例子是电话
So if you think about it a telephone is both a client and a server in that
想象一下，如果一部电话既是客户端又是服务器
When I'm making a placing a call to somebody else
当我给其他人拨一通电话时
I'm the client and that person's phone is the server right
我这边的电话是客户端，而他的电话是服务器，对吧
It's sitting there waiting for calls to come in
它就在那里等待通话进来
And when that call comes in it makes a connection
当通话进来时就创建了一个连接
We talk over the phone and then I hang up either side hangs up
我们通过电话交谈，然后我挂掉电话，或是任意一边挂掉电话(连接就断开了)
So there's a lot of instances out there of some variation of client and server
现实中有许多不同的客户端-服务器模型的例子
And it's a much richer idea in that you can often switch back and forth  the roles of those two parties
而且例子比你想象的要多得多，因为你可以来回切换两者（客户端和服务器）的角色
But it's a pretty universal and a ubiquitous way of thinking about how to set up a network system
但思考如何建立一个网络系统的方式是非常通用的
So in general then the idea is that there's a...system working
通常来说，思路就是...有一个系统在工作
The client is making some requests to the server
当客户端向服务器发送一些请求时
The server does something locally to deal with it
服务器就在本地做一些事情来处理这些请求
It receive it gets information that retrieves from its database the things you might want to buy
它从数据库中检索你可能想买的东西的信息
And then it sends back information say a nicely formatted a web page with all kinds of shopping suggestions
然后它返回信息，比如一个格式化好的网页，上面有各种各样的购物建议
And then the client decides what to do next
然后客户端决定下一步要做什么
So from a hardware perspective the
从硬件的角度来看
Interface to a between the network and
网络和你计算机之间的接口
Your computer is called the NIC or network interface card even though it's not always on a card
叫做 NIC 或是网络接口卡,即使它不总是一张卡
And we really won't talk about hardware at all
当然，我们不会讨论硬件
But what's most interesting from it is that
但最有趣的是
It looks to your computer like an I/O device
它对你的计算机来说就像一个 I/O 设备
And in fact the UNIX uh api for dealing with networks
实际上, UNIX 用于网络处理的 api
Makes it look like a file
使它看起来像一个文件
So in particular just as a disk sits off of a bus
打个比方,总线上有一张磁盘
And you write data to a disk
你向磁盘写入数据
Or you read it from a disk
或者从磁盘中读取数据
Similarly the network sits of a similar bus
同样，网络位于一条类似的总线上
And when you want to send a message you actually do it by writing
当你想要发送信息时，你实际上是通过
To a sort of virtual file that's called the network
向一个叫做网络的虚拟文件写入数据来实现的
And if you want...when you're receiving data you do it by reading
而当你想接收数据时，你通过读取文件来实现
So just as several weeks ago I gave the lecture on I/O
就像几周前我讲 I/O 时说的
It turns out that it's extremely relevant to network programming
它与网络编程非常相关
That's the basic model that was created by the early developers of the sort of standard UNIX
这就是早期标准 UNIX 开发人员创建的基本模型
And now that's carried over not just to UNIX but it's the same model for windows and other operating systems
当然，现在这个模型不仅适用于 UNIX 也适用于 windows 和其他操作系统
So
那么
And now let's just talk a little about what computer networking means
我们现在先讲一点计算机网络的概念
The idea of a network is a collection of systems that are referred to as hosts
网络是一些被称为主机的系统的集合
That are able to communicate with each other over some kind of communication fabric let's call
网络上的主机能够通过某种通信结构相互通交流
It communications system
我们就把它叫做通信系统吧
And they're sort of partitioned into
大多数网络被划分为
Mostly referred to as lands or local area networks
局域网
That you establish within a small region
它们主要是建在小区域内的
And then a wide area network which would be over something the size of a city or perhaps more
接着是广域网络，它可以覆盖一个城市或者更大的区域
And over a enterprise such as CMU it's a very complex set of
在 CMU 校园里，有一个很复杂的网络结构
For example there's wireless base stations that right in this room
例如，这个房间里就有无线基站
That you're interacting with when you're using a wireless system or your your phone
当你使用无线系统或手机时，你就会与之交互
And then there's a whole networking infrastructure within the university
总的来说就是大学里有一套完整的网络基础设施
Then goes to some commercial providers
然后是运营商
At&t in particular that give it access to the commercial internet
比如 At&t，它可以让你接入商业互联网
And then there's another set of network connections hosted by the supercomputing center
此外还有一些网络连接由超级计算中心托管
That give you access to what's called internet2 which is the resource that's used for communicating among universities
它们可以让你访问 internet2，这是用于大学之间交流的网络
So underneath you know when you're doing your networking stuff
所以你至少要知道当你在网络上做一些事情时
There's this amazingly complex combination of things going on
有许多非常复杂的东西在运行
The idea of an internet is supposed is refers to the idea
互联网的概念就是指这个
The general idea of a network of networks
网络的一般概念
Taking for example the local area network that this base station provides
举个例子，这个基站提供的地区网络
And connecting it up to other networks on campus and across the world
会与校园网和世界各地的其他网络连接起来
And when we refer to the capital i internet
补充一下,当我们提到大写 I 的 Internet 时
That refers to the one instance the most significant instance of an internet
指的是那个最大的因特网
So low case i means the sort of general idea of creating a network of networks
而小写 i 的 internet 指的是互联网这一总体概念
Uppercase i(I) is the specific example that we all know and use all the time
大写 i(I) 的英特网是我们一直都知道并使用的一个具体例子
That's organized by a certain set of principles that uses a particular set of protocols and so forth
它是依据一定的原理和协议组织的
And of course we tend to just talk the Internet
当然，我们倾向于只谈论因特网
And most people know that what that really implies is the sort of existing network structure that there is
大多数人都知道这指的是现有的主要网络结构
And that's good enough for the purpose of this course
这对于这门课来说已经足够了
We're not going to talk much about other possible designs one might have for a network
我们不会讨论部分网络可能使用的另一些结构
So most of the low level networking is supported by something called Ethernet
大部分低级网络是由以太网支持的
And the term Ethernet actually has evolved tremendously over time
随着时间的推移，以太网这个术语已经有了很大的发展
So that it's almost more like a brand name that it is in specific technology
所以比起一种特定的技术名称，它更像是一个标志
And the version you're familiar with the wired version of it
你们熟悉有线版本的以太网就是
You have a wire to some sort of a box
你有一根电线连接到某种盒子上
Like that you plug the your Ethernet jacks into
比如你把以太网插孔插进去
And historically those were called hubs
通常那个盒子被称为集线器
And the idea of a hub, it was just a repeater that whatever came into it from one computer
集线器的就像一个中继器,无论什么东西从一台电脑进入它
It would broadcast to all the connected machines
都会被广播到所有与它连接的机器上
And so you only want to do this for maybe a dozen or
而你原本可能需要重复操作十几次
So machines that it's like a party-line they're all hearing what everybody else is saying
而机器就像一只聚会的队伍，它们都在听其他人在说什么
And in fact the original first version the Ethernet did that by everyone interacting over a single cable
事实上，以太网最初是通过每个人用一根电缆进行交互实现的
Carrying essentially radio signals and
这些电缆主要携带了无线电信号
And similarly when you're in this room using a wireless internet
同样的，当你在这个房间里使用无线网的时候
A wireless internet is sort of like a hub and that
无线网就像一个集线器
All the packets that you're sending all across the room
你在房间里发送的所有数据包
They're all sort of making use of the same radio frequencies the same communication channel
它们都使用相同的无线电频率，相同的信道
And there's a protocol for how they detect when two messages get set at the same time and therefore interfere with each other
所以会有一个协议用于检测，两条报文是否会因为同时被发出而相互干扰
So that can only sort of scale up to maybe at most a hundred different
因此无线网可能最多只能扩展到同时让 100 台不同的
Hosts communicating because they're all sharing a single communication channel
主机通信，因为它们共享一个信道
Now in the wired world what's evolved is usually when you buy a box
而有线通信和它区别是，当你买一个“盒子”时
Or you get one from your cable company
或者你可以从有线电公司得到一个
With all those ports in it, it's actually called a router or sometimes a switch in that
它上面有一些端口,它实际上被称为路由器或是交换机
It doesn't broadcast to everyone
它不会向所有人广播
It selectively tries to guess
它有选择地猜测
Is this particular message bound for this particular host
这条报文是发送到这台特定的主机的吗
And only send to that one
然后只发送到那台特定的主机上
And as you know you can take these and wire up
正如你们所知，你们可以把它们连接起来
I think about up to 6 levels deep in an hub
我觉得在一个集线器中至多可以有 6 层连接
And basically create a network of wired connections
基本上，只要建立一个有线连接的网络
And they'll all get from one to the other somehow
它们就可以通过某种渠道从一个网络连接到另一个网络
And then after that it gets more complicated you can add more sophisticated types of switch on top of it
之后当它变得更复杂时，你可以在顶层添加更复杂的交换机
But so the general idea of even an Ethernet is actually a fairly complex thing
虽然以太网的概念很复杂
But it's some sort of conceptual level we can just think of it as a bunch of hosts
但我们可以把它想象成一堆主机
That can talk directly to one another
它们可以直接地相互对话
And then an internet then refers to the idea of taking those local area networks and connecting them together
互联网指的是通过路由器把这些局域网连接起来
Via routers and routers obey a particular protocol based on the address
而路由器应用的特定的协议则
That you're trying to send data to
基于你发送的数据的目标地址
And
然后
And so what you end up with conceptually is a whole bunch of hosts spread potentially all across the world
因此，你最终连接的是一大堆可能分布在世界各地的主机
And then some magical system of routers
接下来要讲的是神奇的路由器系统
That will get a message from one place to the other
它们会把报文将从一个地方传递到另一个地方
Based on a mode of addressing where there's some known address of the hosts
基于已知地址的寻址模式
That you're trying to send to
最终到达你的目标主机
And it will hub through multiple routers to get from one place to the other
它会通过多个路由器，集线器，从一个端点传输到另一个端点
And that's true whether it's on campus
它会四处跃迁，无论是在校园里
Or whether it's hopping all the way around the world
还是在世界各地
And so again there's this huge body of information and knowledge about how that routing works
所以会有许多关于路由器是如何工作
And how its reliable and all that
它为什么可靠的知识
But we're going to just assume that somebody else has figured that out
我们假设其他人已经解决了这些问题
And our job as programmers is just to be able to communicate from one host to another
作为程序员，我们只需要实现在主机之间进行通信
And so how could you design a system where all these diverse systems
那么你如何设计一个系统，让所有这些不同的系统
Made by computers made by different manufacturers operating under different countries with different telecommunications bodies governing bodies and so forth
这些在不同的计算机上运行，由不同的厂商发行，由不同国家的电信机构经营的系统
How can they all work with each other
协同工作
And the requirement is you have to have a protocol you have to have some common set of conventions
答案是必须有一个协议，一些共同的约定
For what messages look like how they get sent
比如报文应该是什么格式，它们怎么被发送
What happens if one of them doesn't make it how do you recover from that and so forth
如果其中一个报文没有成功发送你们怎样恢复它们，等等
And so what does a protocol include well it has to include some way of naming things so that
那么协议包括什么呢? 事实上，它必须包含一些命名规则
If I want to send to some host I have some way of designating
如果我想向某台主机发送报文，我得有一些方法
Who that host is
去指定主机是谁
And then there's the routing system has to have some reliable way of getting my data to that named host
然后是路由系统必须有可靠的方式将我的数据送到指定主机
And that's the delivery mechanism
即可靠的传递机制
And that's usually done and one of the things that we now accept  as universal
如今这个机制已经完成了，而且我们如今已经普遍接受了这一机制
But it really wasn't when it first came out was idea of you take all your data and you divide it into packets
但当这个观点 -- 把你所有的数据分到一个个数据包中 -- 第一次出现的时候,它并未被普遍接受
And packets are typically about a thousand to two thousand bytes
数据包通常是 1000 到 2000 字节
And so if you have a longer message it chops it up into individual packets and sends it across
所以如果你有一条较长的报文，它会被切分成许多单独的数据包，然后发送出去
And all the communication occurs at the packet level
而且所有的通信都发生在数据包这一层
That's different than the historic phone system
这与历史上的电话系统不同
With a connection based system meaning that
电话系统是一个以线路为基础的系统,这意味着
If I was calling somebody there is a dedicated wire set of wires maintained by the phone company
如果我打电话给某人,会有一组由电话公司维护的专用线路
That would be reserved and locked down for our own use
被保留和锁定，仅供我们使用
During the entire duration of that phone call
在整个通话过程中都是如此
So
那么
To get them from one host say A to B
把报文从一个主机 A 发往另一个主机 B
What happens is we want to send a packet
实际上发生的事是我们想传递一个数据包
And that packet will contain some amount of data
数据包中有一部分数据
And the idea of a packet communication then is you put little headers on
数据包通信就是在数据包上附上一个包头
That contain certain routing information see on the front of an envelope of a letter perhaps
包头含有确切的路由信息，就好像信封之于信件
And so and at different points in the way
数据包在发送过程的不同阶段
They'll have different numbers of headers and different protocols or formats for what those headers look like
会有不同数量的包头，而且它们所使用的协议不是完全相同的
So in particular within
所以当
I want to send a message and I'll
我想要发送一条报文的时候
I'll do that and then the software that runs on my machine that handles this
电脑上的软件会帮我完成上述的步骤
Will put a header in front of that describes the internet routing
它会帮我放上一个描述网络路由的包头
And then it will tack a header in front of that talks about the local area network routing that gets used
以及一个描述主机路由的包头
And that's what's referred to as the a PH the packet header for the internet protocol
这就是我们所说的基于互联网协议的包头 PH
And FH1 the frame header for this particular message being sent within this local network
而 FH1 则是指在本地网络中发送的特定消息的帧头
And then the network interface card or the adapter here
接下来，网卡或适配器负责
Is then responsible for putting that out over this local communication of capability
在报文可以在本地通信后，把它发送出去
And then that gets received at the other end by the network adapter at the receivers direction
最后报文会被接收端的网络适配器接受
It will put up its own frame header on it to pass it in
适配器会在它上面放上自己的帧头以接收它
And that then gets stripped off
之后它们(帧头)会被剥离
So that all hosts be set sees is the the data that gets sent
所以最后所有的主机都只会看到数据部分
But this idea of putting headers in front and at times sort of what they call encapsulation that
这种在数据包前添上“头”的做法叫封装
I'll take this big packet and I'll just tack some more information on top to the front of it header information
我拿到这个数据包之后就在它的最上层添上头信息
And I'll send through the rest of it just as a set of bytes
然后我将把剩下的部分作为一组字节发送
So the internet that we know and love the capital I internet
我们了解和喜爱的网络是大写 I 的因特网
Then has a particular set of protocols that are you've probably heard the terms
他有一些特殊的协议，你们可能已经听过这些术语了
One is called the IP the internet protocol
其中有一个协议叫互联网地址协议即 IP
Which is the one that defines ideas about how do you get how do you name hosts on the internet
它定义了你们命名主机的方法
And how do you send packets
和发送包的方法
And they're referred to sometimes is datagrams
有时也把包叫做数据包
Meaning that a packet is just a single entity that gets sent from point A to point B
这意味着数据包只是一个从点 A 发往点 B 的实体
And the underlying IP doesn't guarantee delivery so
而处于底层的 IP 并不能保证包被成功传递
So it's based on what they call best
它基于一种“尽力而为”的传输机制
Effort communication meaning that at each step along the way
意为在传输过程中的每个节点
If for example things are good then it will just send this packet along
假如数据还是完好的话，那么传输将继续
If there's too much congestion
如果线路太堵塞
There's been a you know somebody's turned on their microwave oven and
比如有人启动了微波炉
It's set up some radio frequency interface interference
这时会产生一些射频接口干扰
Then at the IP level it just drops that packet and says whoops
那么在 IP 层数据包就会丢失，然后它会说，啊，我搞砸了
I screwed up sorry it doesn't even say sorry it just does it silently
它甚至不会道歉，只是默默的让数据包丢失
And then you can as a programmer make use of that very global level
所以作为一个程序员，你应该学会利用所有网络层次
So normally as a programmer you don't really want to program at that level
但你通常不会想在那一个层面编程的
Because you'll send packets and they will get there
因为大部分情况下数据包都能正常传输
But you can if you want to and it's called UDP a protocol
但如果你想了解的话，它叫做 UDP 协议
It's just a small software layer over IP
它只是在比 IP 所在层高的一层上的一个小软件
And there's some applications
而在一些应用中
That you'll see for example in the computer game world where you want to send information really fast and if some information gets dropped it's not a big deal
举个例子，电脑游戏中，如果因为你想尽快发出消息，而导致有一些信息被你漏掉，那没什么大不了的
That people actually program at that level
这就是 UDP 层编程的一个例子
We won't really talk about that
我们不会讨论它
The more common protocol that gets used and carries 99% of internet traffic is what's called TCP(transmission control protocol)
更常见的一种协议 -- 有超过 99 % 的网络流量都在通过它传输 -- 叫做 TCP 协议
And that provides a reliable the equivalent of telephone connection
它提供了一种和电话所用的连接方式一样可靠的连接方式
That I can reliably send data from point A to point B
我可以放心的从点 A 往点 B 发送数据
As many bytes as I like
任意字节的数据都可以
It's a guaranteed delivery
它的传输能力是有保证的
It's sometimes fast and sometimes not but it's there
虽然传输速度时快时慢，但它总是稳定的
And it's built on top of the IP of this datagram
它处于数据包的 IP 层之上
Meaning that it has to take whatever you're sending and slice it up into these single packets
这意味着它必须接收你发送的所有数据并将其分割成这些单独的数据包
If one of them doesn't get sent it will resend it until it gets there
如果有一个数据包没有被送达，它就会重复发送直到它被送达
They have to deal with the fact that packets can travel different paths and one can get ahead of the other in transmission
它们还需要处理一个问题：数据包可以通过不同的路径传输，所以有些原本位于后面的数据包可能率先完成传送
And so it has to reorder them in the correct sequence
所以我们需要将它们按正确的顺序重新排列
And so there's a lot of stuff under it but
这一步涉及到很多知识
We'll just assume that it kind of works
但我们只要假设它起作用就行了
And so you can just rely think about it is I have a stream connection
你们可以想象一下，我有一个串流连接
I can send from A to B and B can send a stream of data back to me
我可以从 A 往 B 发送数据流然后 B 也可以反过来给我发送数据流
And we're all happy
我们都会很高兴
And so that's the version that looks like file I/O
这就是把它想象成文件 I/O 的版本
I just keep writing to a file and it's sending packets over the network to the other end
我持续向文件写入数据，它则不断地通过网络向另一端发送数据包
And then the other side can be sending stuff to me
当然另一端也可以向我发送数据
And I'm just reading it and I'm just reading bytes of data
但我只是读取数据
Not worrying about how that got broken up into individual packets
我并不关心它是怎么被分解成独立的数据包的
And so that's referred to as the sockets interface
当然，这是通过 socket 接口实现的
And you'll hear the term socket programming and that's exactly what we're talking about
你会听到 socket 编程这个术语，这就是我们要讲的内容
And so from a sort of software system
从软件系统
Than software hardware system then
和软硬件系统层面观察
The client and the server are both implemented as application programs
客户端和服务器都是以应用程序的形式
At the respective endpoints on their hosts
在其主机上的相应端点处被实现的
And they make use of software and libraries that run at some combination of the user level and at the kernel level
它们使用的软件和库是由用户态和核心态共同运行的
And therefore I have access to direct resources
因此我可以直接访问资源
And so
而且
I as a programmer or an application programmer then make use of this software api
我作为一个应用程序员可以利用这个 api
That lets me do socket programming
它可以让我进行 socket 编程
And it's based on gives directly supports TCP/IP
而且对 TCP/IP 提供直接的支持
So first of all we're going to talk most of the time about what's called IPv4
那么首先我们先了解一下在大多数时候，什么叫 IPv4
A version 4 which is the one that's been running for since the 1980s I think early 1980s
那是一个自 20 世纪 80 年代起实施的第四代互联网协议
And it's the standard and we'll talk very only mentioned very briefly the idea of what's called IPv6
而且是现行标准，然后我们只会简要的提一下 IPv6 的概念
Which is sort of a next-generation version
它则是下一代技术
So the idea of a IPv4 and this is now we're talking about IP
IPv4 即我们现在所说的 IP 地址就是
And and this is true of TCP as well is that an address is actually just 32 bits
一个 32 位的地址，这对 TCP 也适用
But it's usually expressed in what they call dotted decimal form
通常这被叫做“点分十进制”格式
And you've seen these addresses before
这类地址你之前已经见过了
That it's 4 decimal numbers
它有 4 个十进制数
And they can only range between 0 and 255
这四个数只能在 0 和 255 之间
Because each one of them is a single bytes worth of information
因为他它们中的每一个数都只能由一个字节的信息描述
So we're used to writing things in hex now in this course
在这个课程中，我们曾用 16 进制表示过这些数字
But we're going to write it as each byte is written as a decimal digit
但以后我们将把它们书写成十进制格式
And they're actually passed and stored in
事实上，它们以一种叫
What's called network byte order which is big endian byte order
网络字节序的顺序被传递和储存，这种顺序是一种大端字节顺序
And so we have to worry about the whole big endian vs. good endian thing
我们应考虑大端字节顺序
When we're doing network programming
在网络编程中的好处
And you can actually learn a lot there's a whole levels of how the different bytes mean
另外你会了解到 IP 地址的四段字节都代表了不同层次的信息
But for example any ip address it starts with 128.2 is at CMU
举个例子，任何以 128.2 开头的 IP 地址都在 CMU
I think and then
我想本质上就是
And so essentially CMU owns that part of the IP address space
CMU 拥有这部分IP地址空间
Which if you think about that's approximately 2^64
这个空间大概包含了 2^64 个 IP 地址
2 to the...no,not 2^64,2^16 different IP addresses available for use by campus
不对，不是 2^64，是 2^16 个给校园用户使用的不同 IP 地址
And as I mentioned there's a newer version called IPv6
就像我提到过的，有一个新版的互联网协议叫做 IPV6 协议
That gives you a 128-bit addresses
它会给你一个 128 位的地址
You can imagine actually that if you think about how many nodes are there in the internet
你们可以试着想象一下互联网上到底有多少个节点
If a 4 byte address is only 2^32 so that's 4 billion
如果地址是 4 字节的，那么就只有 2^32 个也即 40 亿个节点
And I don't know about you but I have a lot of different things that use IP
我不知道你们是怎么样的，但我有许多不同的东西要用到 IP 地址
I have a phone,I have two laptops,I have a couple desktops
我有一台手机，两台笔记本电脑还有几台台式机
So if all of..if every one of us used multiple IP addresses then actually the world would be out of them right
所以如果我们每个人都要用到多个 IP 地址那么实际上世界上所需要的 IP 地址就超额了对吧
There's seven billion people in the world not all of whom have access to the internet
地球上有 70 亿人，虽然不是所有人都会使用网络
But a large fraction of them do
但有很大一部分都是会使用网络的
And so there's a whole kind of crazy way of dealing with the multitude of possible IP addresses
所以现在有一种疯狂的方式来解决大量可能需要的 IP 地址
So the obvious thing would be well let's just allocate a lot more addresses
很明显，我们需要分配更多地址
And jump let's just skip 64 bits and go right to 128 and that's the idea behind IPv6
从 64 位地址扩增到到 128 位地址就是 IPv6 的思想
But quite honestly this has been one of those technologies that's been out there for over 15 years
但说实话，这是一项已经存在了 15 年的技术
And still has a very low level of adoption so
但到今天它的采纳率仍然很低
It's still a future technology
所以它仍是一项未来的技术
People have basically figured out all these crazy schemes to make use of just stick within the 4 byte limit
人们基本上已经想出了所有只需要 4 个字节位置的方案
Okay so let's start talking the program the sort of programmer perspective on this
那么，现在让我们从程序员的角度思考吧
And this is one area where you'll wish you weren't programming in C
这是一个你希望自己不使用 C 语言来编程的领域
But you are
但
So there's a lot of really crufty stuff
这里有很多混乱的东西
And it was all developed most of the software protocols were conceived before C even was what it is today
大多数软件协议在如今使用的 C 语言出现之前就被构思好了
So like the Kernighan and Ritchie book you have is called the second edition
就像你们使用的 Kernighan 和 Ritchie 的书（《C 程序设计语言》）是第二版
And it's based on what was called ANSI C or ISO C
它基于一个叫做 ANSI C 或是 ISO C 的协议
But these all date before that they date back to the original Kernighan and Ritchie
它的历史可以追溯到 Kernighan 和 Ritchie 的书首次出版的年代
So for example void* did not exist in that era
举个例子，那个时代还没有 void*
And so you use char* as a generic pointer
你需要用 char* 定义空类型指针
And so there's just a lot of stuff in this programming
所以你会觉得网络编程中有许多
Interface where you go wow that is really crufty and that that truth is yes you're right
接口很混乱，实际上你是对的
So in particular there's a lot of different structures that are defined and
实际上，它定义了很多不同的结构体
One of them is called an in_addr which means internet address
其中有一个叫做“in_addr”的关于网络地址的结构体
And it's just defined to be a 32-bit unsigned number
它定义了一个 32 位无符号数
And in general as I mentioned there
就像我刚才所说的
The so called network byte order whoever designed the original protocols was a fan of big endian addressing
最初协议中的的网络字节序的设计者一定是个喜欢用大端字节顺序进行处理的人
And so that's what it is even though actually most of the machines that are out there in this world are little endian
而且这就是即使世界上大部分机器都是用的小端字节序，网络仍用大端字节序的原因
And so there's a set of standard library functions
当然，你可以用许多标准库函数
That you use to convert between network order and host order
来实现网络字节顺序和主机字节顺序间的转换
And the idea of it is now if I run my software on a little endian or a big endian machine
不论我在大端字节序或是小端字节序的机器上运行网络软件时
These functions will do the right thing
上述函数都会让我的机器正常运行
So if I just use these standard libraries
所以即使我只使用这些标准库
Then I don't have to worry about porting it every time I change the word ordering of a machine
我都不用担心每次机器的字节顺序改变时需要手动转换
One of the things you'll notice here is
在此你可能会注意到一件事
There is no function to convert 64-bit data between a network order and host order so
这些函数中没有用于转化 64 位数据的函数
I don't know what people do when I do it I just write my own thought,my own functions to do it
我不知道人们都是怎么做的，但就我个人，我会自己编写一个函数来实现这一功能
Or I don't because I know my other end is a little endian machine
我也可能不会这么做，因为我知道另一端的机器肯定是小端字节序的
So anyways these are already some functions you'll start seeing for that look like network conversion software
不管怎样，这里列出了一些你会遇到的现存的函数，它们看起来就像网络转换软件一样
And as I mentioned the addresses are written in a dotted decimal form
就像我提到的，这些地址是以点分十进制的格式书写的
And it's also big endian
它也是大端结尾的
So if I were to write in hex 128 is of course 0x80
所以假如我要用 16 进制书写，128 就是 0x80
So that's the most significant byte of the IP address
这是 IP 地址最重要的字节
And then there is a set of functions api calls you can use to convert between this dotted decimal format
接下来是可以帮助你进行点分十进制
And the actual just a 32-bit unsigned int
和 32 位无符号整形相互转换的函数/api
And actually it used to be there is
实际上
You might see some older presentations where they use different names for this
在一些旧的演示文稿上，你可能见过一些它们的曾使用过名称
But the most recent version api calls this
但最新的版本中，api 调用的是
The presentation version the dotted decimal they referred to it as a presentation
这里所演示的，以点分十进制表达的 IP 地址
And you can look up the and it's in the book too what the calls to these look like
你可以在书上找到这些内容，书上有这些调用的格式
But you probably don't or very seldom
你可能从未或是很少
When you're thinking about I want to go to Google
想过当你想访问 Google 的时候
You don't think about what its IP address is you just go to www.google.com
你并不会思考它的 IP 地址是多少，而是直接访问 www.google.com
And for everything you do you refer to it by this
当你访问其它网站时你也会这么做
It would have referred called internet domain names which is a hierarchical naming system
www.google.com 叫做域名，是一个分级命名系统
Whereas you know there's .edu is for educational institutions
就像你知道的 .edu 是给教育机构使用的
.com is for commercial
.com 是用于商业的
.net is general networking uh many countries have their own suffix
.net 就是一般的网络，其实很多国家都有自己的后缀
So you know .de is for Germany and so forth
比如 .de 是德国的后缀，等等
And so those are called the first level domain names
这些叫做一级域名
And then there's a hierarchical naming structure under that
而这之下是一个分层的命名体系
And
然后
There's actually an interesting question of okay
实际上这里有个有趣的问题
How do I then map from those hierarchical names those domain names into this dotted decimal or the 32 bit IP address
我如何从这些域名映射到点分十进制或是 32 位的 IP 地址
And the job of that is by a very large distributed system called the DNS the domain name system
其实这些工作是由一个非常大的分布式系统完成的，它叫做 DNS ，即域名系统
Where the only sort of centrally managed part of it is at the top level
它唯一的核心管理模块在最顶层
So for each of these first level domain names
对于每一个一级域名
There's a collection a very large collection of machines that keep track of all the IP addresses
有一个非常大的机器集群用于跟踪所有
That map to one of those first level domain names
映射到这些一级域名的 IP 地址
And then for example CMU maintains its own naming authority
举个例子，CMU
So anything that says something .cmu.edu
对任何 xxx.cmu.edu 形式的域名有命名权
There's local DNS servers within CMU
CMU中有一些本地 DNS 服务器
That are picking apart ok where should you know
帮你分离出一些...你知道的
If I say cs.cum.edu what would be the IP address for that
比如说我要知道 cs.cmu.edu 对应的 IP 地址
Well and it's actually pretty interesting how this is managed because it's all it's totally decentralized
事实上，完成这一步的方法非常有趣，因为它是完全分散的
There's a whole set of protocols that govern how naming is done
会有一整套协议用于控制如何命名域名
But conceptually we can think of it as just this big database
但从概念上，我们可以把它想象成一个
That gives me a mapping
给我特定映射的巨型数据库
Where I can give a domain name and it will get back to me a one or more IP addresses
如果我给它一个域名，它会返回一个或多个 IP 地址给我
I can give an IP address and it will come back with one or more domain names
我也可以给它一个 IP 地址，它会返回一个或多个域名
Oh and so there's actually an application you can run
哦，实际上你可以运行一个程序
On most machines called nslookup and there's another one called dig
它在大部分机器上叫做 nslookup ，还有一个叫 dig 的程序
That you can use to find basically probe the DNS
你可以用它们来探测 DNS
And find in either direction you can look at the given a domain name you can find its IP address
给一个的域名，你会得到它的 IP 地址
Given an IP address you can find its domain name
给一个 IP 地址你就可以找到它的域名
And we'll so I'll show you some code that
我将给你们展示一些代码
Just as an example of how you do the programming
它是一个你们编程时可以参考的示例
I'll just show that momentarily called hostname
我将展示那个暂时命名为 hostname 的东西
So just some examples
接下来是一些例子
You know if I look up some address like the website for the computer science school computer science
如果我查询一些地址，比如计算机科学学院的网址
Using nslookup
用 nslookup
It comes back can people see this okay
它会返回...你们能看到吗？
Doing it bigger?It's okay
把它放大好吗？可以了
So this is what nslookup looks like and this stuff here just tells you
所以这就是 nslookup 的样子，它刚刚告诉你
You know who where was the actual directory entry in the which DNS server actually gave these information back
哪个 DNS 服务器返回了这些信息
And it says that
它还告知了
www.cs.cum is actually a synonym for a weirder one called WEB-LB.SRV.cum.edu
www.cs.cum 实际上是一个更奇怪的域名 WEB-LB.SRV.cum.edu 的代名词
And its IP address is 128.2 like you'd expect
它的 IP 地址是以 128.2 开头的，就像你们猜测的那样
217.13
接着是 217.13
And of course that works not just at CMU but I can
当然，它不仅适用于 CMU 内的网络，我也可以
You know go ask about what Stanford is up to
用它查询斯坦福大学计算机系域名的相关信息
And it will come back and its IP address is something 171.64
它会返回它的 IP 地址，171.64 开头的一串数字
And that's been managed by that and you'll see again it's
这个域名是由那个 DNS 服务器管理的，你会再次看到
I asked for www.cs.stanford.edu it said well the real name of that is cs.stanford.edu
我访问了 www.cs.stanford.edu，而它的真实域名是 cs.stanford.edu
And this actually is a point that the
这实际上是一个关键点
The mapping between domain names
域名和
And internet addresses is not one-to-one
IP 地址间的映射不是一一对应的
You can have multiple domain names that refer to the same internet address
可以有多个域名对应同一个 IP 地址
But you can also have multiple internet addresses
也可以有多个 IP 地址
Excuse me
稍等一下
That's weird
有点问题
So like twitter.com when I ask for it it comes back with four different addresses
那么，比如像 twitter.com，当我查询它的 IP 地址时，nslook 返回了四个不同的地址
And if I do the exact same thing again
如果我再重复一次
Mmm came back but yeah
Mmm 是的
You see it came back with
你可以看到它返回了
The same no not even the same addresses
和上一次不完全相同的地址
It came back for example here the one that ends with .6 that wasn't in that first was
比如说这次返回的 .6 结尾的地址上一次没有出现
So it came back with a slightly different set of addresses and a somewhat different order
简单来说，它返回了一组有轻微不同的地址，而且它的返回顺序也变了
And the idea of that is that actually has multiple servers
出现这个现象实际是因为它有许多的服务器
So when I send to twitter.com or Google or any of these major servers
当我请求访问 twitter.com 或是 Google 或是任何主流网站
There's not just one place in the internet that's handling everybody's google traffic
网络中有不止一处位置处理每个人的 google 流量
There's thousands of places spread around the world
它们分布在全球的上千个地点
And the way they get you there is by playing tricks with the DNS
而把你分配到哪台服务器是由 DNS 决定的
That Google is constantly sending updates to the it maintains its own DNS servers
Google 持续的对它的 DNS 服务器进行升级
So it's constantly changing them
它持续的改变它们
And it will actually give you different addresses depending on where in the world you're located as well
然后 DNS 会根据你的现实位置给你不同的网络地址
To try and provide a server that's sort of reasonably close to you geographically so
并尽可能让一台最靠近你地理位置的服务器为你提供服务
There's all just all kinds of tricks that happen through DNS
这就是 DNS 的所有作用
That is part of the way they can sort of manage this huge set of addresses
这就是它处理如此庞大的地址集的方式
And then there's some other domain names that don't have any IP address
当然，也有一些域名不映射任何 IP 地址
That they're somewhere in the hierarchy that hierarchical naming system
它们在分级命名系统的某个地方
But they're not actually referring to a particular host
但它们不对应一台特定的主机
So it's a multi-multi mapping
所以映射可以是多对多的
In the...the api set reflects
api 集合反映了这一点
It so this is just going what I told you they sometimes one-to-one
这就是我刚刚讲的它们有时一一对应
Sometimes many domain names refer to the same address
有时许多域名对应同一个地址
Sometimes one name maps to multiple addresses that change over time
有时一个域名对应多个地址，而这些地址时刻都在变化
And then there's some where it's a valid name
也有一些合法域名
But it doesn't have an IP address it doesn't have a host associated with a question
不对应任何 IP 地址，因为它没有关联一台主机，有问题吗？
[student asking]
[学生提问]
Oh how do I get...how do you get your own IP address
好的，你怎么得到你自己的 IP 地址对吧
Well all you have to beg borrow or you have to either borrow or buy them
你需要做的只是租借或者买下一个
So for example at CMU there is some number of what they call statically allocated ip addresses
举个例子，CMU 有一定数量的静态分配的 IP 地址
Where it's just fixed assigned to that machine and you can register form and request them through computing services
它固定分配给一些机器，假如你需要使用它们完成一些服务，你可以填表申请
But most you don't have that most you get one that's I signed dynamically
但你们中的大部分人都是得不到那部分 IP 地址的，大多数时候你们得到的 IP 地址都是动态的
So there's a pool of addresses that you basically they call them leasing
有一个地址池提供租借服务
That you are assigned with for a while
它们在一定的时间内会分配给你
And then but it could possibly be reassigned to someone else
但它们也可能被分配给其他人
And that's part of the way it can manage
这就是为什么
You know somewhat limited set of IP addresses
在 IP 地址数量有限的情况下每个人都有使用的机会
So the idea of like I said that the main
就像我说的我们进行网络连接时
Uh way we'll think about it is in terms of what's called TCP
利用的主要方式叫做 TCP
And it says connection oriented protocol
它是一种面向连接的协议
Where I establish a connection from one host establishes a connection to another host
一台主机创建一个通向另一台主机的连接
And they can communicate to each other sending arbitrarily long streams of bytes to each other
它们可以通过给对方发送任意长度的字节流实现相互间的通信
And so the connection is then two hosts that can talk to each other
因此连接就是两台主机间的交流
And each of those endpoints is referred to as a socket
连接的每一端都是一个 socket
And so I can and a socket is both an IP address
socket 包括了 IP 地址和
And what's called a port number
端口号
So there's a 16 byte, 16 bit number for every connection
对于每一个连接都有一个 16 位的数字
That's referred to as its port
它们被称为端口号
And the reason for that is just because I'm talking to a particular machine
需要它是因为当我和一台特定的机器通信时
That machine can support different services
它会提供许多不同的服务
It can provide SSH connections it can provide FTP connections
比如说 SSH 服务，FTP 服务
It can host a mail server,it can host a web server
它也可以作为邮件服务器或是网络服务器
So a particular machine might have a multitude of different services
所以一台机器可能有大量不同的服务
And so those are differentiated from each other with what are called port numbers
而这些服务会通过端口号进行区分
And similarly as a client might have connections to dozens of hosts going at any given time
同样的，客户机可能同时和几十台主机连接
I'm cruising the web I'm you know doing all that different stuff
我在网上冲浪或是干其它事
And that's all differentiated the client and that there's different ports
每个客户端的情况都不一样，提供各个服务的端口也不一样
Associated with your different programs that are running
到底是哪个端口提供服务和你运行的程序有关
And so a port then is a 16-bit integer
端口就是一个 16 位的整数
That identifies which particular endpoint is
它标识了到底是哪个特定的端点在跟它通信
Being communicated with it either the client side or the server side
到底是客户端还是服务端在跟它通信
And typically at the client side these are assigned dynamically
特别地，在客户端上端口是动态分配的
And they referred to as ephemeral ports meaning
它们被叫做临时端口
They only are assigned for the limited duration that you have a connection with that
它们只会在一定的时间内被分配，通常是有连接需要使用它们时
That you're maintaining that connection
或是你要维持一个连接时
And then there has to be some way if I'm going to contact
那么，肯定会有一种方法让我...
And I want to know the dns will tell me what the IP address is of say google.com
假设我想知道 google.com 的 IP 地址，DNS 会告诉我
But I have to know that
但我其实想知道
Am I communicating with its web service which is port 80 or https secure socket is a different report number
我到底是在使用 80 端口上的网络服务还是其它某个端口上的 https 服务
So which service I'm asking for
到底是哪个服务呢
And there's a standard list what are called well-known ports
其实有一串标准端口，它们被称为公认端口
That are that I can contact at the server end to get the particular service I'm looking for
我可以用服务器的公认端口去获得特定的服务
And those are assigned there's a big waste of port assignments
这些端口是固定分配给某种服务的，这对端口分配来说是个巨大的浪费
And so the again that's part of the sort of
它们是
A whole set of internet standards it's the identifiers for the different ports
互联网标准的一部分，也是不同端口的标识符
What services those are and how those particular protocols work
它们告知了端口提供何种服务，以及对应协议的内容
So when I have a connection then
那么当我有一个连接时
As I mentioned uh think of it as a connection then is as a
就像我提到的，把它们看做
Link between two machines based on some known port typically at the server end
两台机器间的连接，这个连接是基于服务器上的一些公认端口
And a dynamically assigned or ephemeral port assigned at the client end
和主机上的一个动态分配端口或是临时端口实现的
And I can refer to then that connection then is identified by the combination of the hosts at the two ends
我想说的是，连接是由连接两端的主机
And the ports that they're using
和它们各自使用的端口共同识别的
And in general then it's the job of the kernel to differentiate the different connections that are coming into a machine
通常情况下，核心态需要区分来到这台机器的不同连接
And figure out which software which process to wake up
并且为各个连接启动它们需要的软件和进程
When a data you know when some data arrives from another machine
当其他机器上的数据到达你的机器时
In which actual program running on that machine will make use of that data
到底是什么程序在利用它们呢
And that's done by associating for each of the ports, a particular process executing program
实际上，每个端口都有特定的进程执行程序
That's going to handle those particular requests
处理这些请求
And it's totally possible for a client to be interacting with a single server over different ports
另外，一个客户端同时和单一服务器上的不同端口通信也是完全可能的
But those are considered to be different connections and
但这需要用到不同的连接
And so they don't really interfere with each other
所以它们不会互相干扰
So that's what I mentioned is this is what we refer to as sockets programming or the sockets interface
接下来要讲的就是我提到的 socket 编程，或是叫 socket 接口
It was developed sort of as the internet was evolving in the late 70s and early 80s
它是伴随着互联网的演变在 19 世纪 70 年代末到 80 年代初发展起来的
So socket then as I said is certain logically one end
socket 其实是逻辑层面上的一个端点
One of the two ends of a connection
即连接的其中一端
And from an application point of view you'll see it as a file descriptor
从应用程序的角度，你可以把它看做一个文件描述符
Just the low-level file stuff that you've already seen that you can do reading and writing from
即系统底层可以让你进行读写操作的文件，你们之前已经见过了
Um
嗯
And so that's the sort of mental model that is provided by the socket interface
它就是 socket 接口提供的一种关键模型
But it's a very different you know the actual implementation of network
但它和网络的实现还是有很大的区别的
When you write to a socket
当你对 socket 文档进行写入时
It's firing up all kinds of network stuff whereas you write to a disk
它会启动各种与网络有关的东西，就像你对磁盘写入时
It's operating a disk controller
会操作一个磁盘控制器一样
So at the hardware level and even at the lower levels of software they're very different beings
虽然在硬件层面或是软件底层它们的本质有很大的区别
But you as an application programmer see some commonality there
但你作为一个应用程序员需要看到它们的一些共同点
Okay so let's jump right into the API
好的，那么我们直接进入 API 的部分吧
And again this is a place where you'll wish you were programming in a language
在这个部分你是会想要使用含有“类”方法
That had a type hierarchy
的语言来编程的
But you aren't,you're programming in C
但你并不能用，你得用 C 语言来编程
There's a type, there's a zillion structs that you kind of have to get familiar with
你需要熟悉这里的许多结构体
But one's called a sockaddr and basically it's just a 16 bytes worth of stuff
其中一个叫做 sockaddr，它本质上只是一个 16 字节长的东西
Where the only thing that's special here is that the leading two bytes
唯一特殊的地方就是头两个字节
Designate what type of socket this is
指明了这个 socket 是什么类型的
And particularly be different whether it's a TCP socket
举个例子，它到底是 TCP socket
An IPv6 socket a UDP socket
还是 IPv6 socket，或是 UDP socket
And all those will have different numbers
会有不同的数字告诉你
A different constant in there that tells you which type of socket it is
有一个常量告诉你它到底是哪种类型的 socket
And then the high level the sockets in a lot of the programs don't need to know
但是很多高级程序不需要知道 socket 的类型
You know which type of connection this is
或是这到底是哪种连接
They can just deal with they basically call other software to deal with that
它们大多会调用其它软件来解决这个问题
So that's why it's referred to as being families specific
这就是为什么它被称为特殊族
And then the socket stuff isn't even necessarily referred to the internet the Internet
这些东西对因特网来说并不必要
And so there's a more specific one called a sockaddr_in
还有一个更特殊的结构体叫做 sockaddr_in
That is used for IPv4 sockets
它用于 IPv4 socket
Not IPv6
而不是 IPv6 socket
And so in particular it fills in fields one is called the port which as I mentioned is 16 bits
它包含了许多字段，其中有一个是关于端口的，我提到过它是 16 位的
And then the IP address
它之后是有关 IP 地址的字段
The 4 byte IP address both of which are in
4 字节的 IP 地址字段
Even if you're running the software on a x86 machine
即使你在 x86 机器上运行它
These should be in big endian order
它俩应该都是大端字节序的
And you'll see that this is what I mean that this is sort of a
你会发现这就是我说的
C version of subtyping if you know something like C++ or java
C 语言的一种子类，如果你了解 C++ 或者 java
Or you know a language with type inheritance
或者任何一个有类型继承的语言的话
That you can think of it as a sockaddr_in a sort of a subclass of a sockaddr
你可以把 sockaddr_in 看做 sockaddr 的一个子类
Right it has more information it's compatible with
对吧，它兼容 socket
But has more information than a socket
但有比 socket 更多的信息
And then there's another type of for IPv6 has a different kind of
而对于 IPv6 有另一种
Struct that they fill in for its information
结构体用于储存信息
And then they pat it out with 8 bytes of zeros
之后这里会用 8 字节的 0 把它补充完整
Just because this particular protocol doesn't require the full 16 bytes
因为这个协议并不需要用完 16 个字节
Okay so this is sort of what it looks like to operate a full-blown Client-server system from a programmers perspective
这就是程序员对客户端-服务器系统的完整流程的理解
And we're going to for the rest of today and all of Thursday go through all these steps
在这节课的剩余时间和周四的整节课上，我们将一步步实现整个过程
And you as a programmer are actually going to have to understand each of these steps
而你们作为程序员必须理解每一个步骤
What they do?what they mean?And how to use them
每一步在做什么？它们为什么要这么做？怎么利用它们？
The good news is there's some pretty standard patterns here
好消息是一些最基本的模块已经是现成的了
And so you can often grab some existing code say out of the book to use that will make this not as painful as it might look
你们可以从书本之外的一些地方找到现存的代码并使用它们，这会使这一部分没有想象中的那么痛苦
So but the overall idea of this this picture then is
从整体上理解这个图片
Sorry can't get use the fast way my remote doesn't work
不好意思，遥控坏了
On the the right hand side refers to the steps that the server has to go through
图片的右半部分是服务器需要处理的步骤
And the left hand side is what the client does
左半部分则是客户端要处理的步骤
So the upper right is what it takes to set up a server
右上角是设置一个服务器的步骤
That is then a program that's running there
它上面有一个程序在运行
Ready to receive connections from a client and perform various services
准备接受客户端发送的连接请求并提供各种服务
And so obviously before the client can do anything the server has to exist
很显然，有了服务器之后客户端才能利用它
So that has to be the first step in setting things up
所以这是创建整个系统的第一步
And then we have to...we'll fire up a cert a client that will make use of this service
接着我们要启动一个使用这些服务的客户端
And then there'll be what's referred to as a session
接下来有一个叫做会话的部分
Meaning a kind of back and forth communication between the client and server
它指的是客户端和服务器之间来回通信
Doing whatever they're going to do,this is not specific to any particular application
并完成它们要做的事，任何应用程序都需要这个部分
And like I said it will involve you'll see rio_ remember those were reliable I/O
它包括了 rio_ 开头的多个函数，你们应该还记得我们讲过
Functions we talked about as part of the UNIX I/O
它们是 UNIX I/O 系统中的一部分可靠的 I/O 函数
So it's a way to read and write in a rom and handle some of the quirks of low-level I/O
可以用于读写 rom 并处理一些底层 I/O 的操作
But basically this is sending and receiving messages over the internet
但它们主要还是用于发送和接受网络上的信息
And then once that's done
上述部分都完成之后
Typically then the client will close its connection sort of equivalent of hanging up its phone
客户端就会结束连接，就像挂电话一样
And say ok I'm done
相当于在说“我完成了”
And then sometime later or maybe never depending on what kind of web you know service this is
在一些情况下，当然你可能永远都遇不到这些情况，它们是否出现取决于服务器到底在运行哪种服务
If the server wants to shut down
如果服务器想要主动结束连接
It has its own a collection of calls that it makes to stop that service
它有让自己停止相应服务的函数集
So anyways just to kind of give you the landscape of what this picture means
不管怎样，你们应该对这幅图片有一个大致的了解了
So we're going to sort of jump into
我们接下来将直接学习
The middle this the top level and we'll focus
我到底是从上往下讲还是
Actually which will we focus on
我到底怎么讲
Well we'll talk to some level in parallel
好吧，我还是一个模块一个模块的讲吧
Because there's a lot of commonality as you can see between what goes on with the server and what goes on with the client
因为这样你就可以看到客户端和服务器上的函数的共同点
Yeah and so actually the top level call this one called getaddrinfo is the way that
最上方的 getaddrinfo 函数
It sort of...
它算是
Initiate things and actually does the lookup to map from a domain name to a IP address
整个流程的开端，它实际上是用于查找从域名到 IP 地址的映射
So we'll cover that later
我之后会详细讲解这个过程
So the first step in on either side then and creating a connection is a call to a function called socket
所以客户端和服务器要做的第一步都是通过调用 socket 函数来创建连接
And the reason I wanted to blackboard was to help you keep track of this
为了方便你们记录，我会把这些内容写到黑板上
So the first call is a doesn't do much
第一个调用实际上作用不大
Oh and that's why the function call is socket
因此这个函数被称为 socket
But the
而且
It only happens within the application
它只在这个程序内部起作用
It doesn't make a use of any part of the operating system doesn't send anything over the network
它不会使用操作系统，也不会往网络上发送任何内容
And the idea is to basically say hey I want to create a socket
这一步只是为了创建一个 socket
And it's given three arguments
它有三个参数
The first which is AF_INET
第一个参数叫 AF_INET
All these upper case on names are constants that are built in or included in the various .h files that
请注意，所有字母大写的参数都是包含在各种 .h 文件里的常量
That you include in writing this code
你们写代码的时候应该包含这些头文件
And AF_INET just means it's a IPv4 so 32-bit addresses
AF_INET 告诉我们它是一个 32 位的 IPv4 地址
And then the second parameter is says you want a SOCK_STREAM
第二个参数 SOCK_STREAM
And that refers to a TCP connection
表明了这个连接是一个 TCP 连接
It's referred to as a stream connection because like I said you get to send as many bytes as you like a stream of bytes
它也被称为流连接，因为你可以发送任意字节数据流
Either direction
而且是双向的
And then
下一个参数
Zero protocol
则是 0
Well I guess it must not be very interesting because I set it to zero
嗯，它可能没什么用，因为我把它设成了 0
So we don't need to do anything in this particular case
我们在这个例子中不用做任何操作
There are man pages on this by the way which
关于如何进行 socket 编程有一些文档
If you just tried to learn all sockets programming by reading men pages you'd go crazy
但如果你想通过读那些东西来学会 socket 编程，你会疯掉的
But once you kind of have the idea of it the man pages are pretty useful
不过一旦你领悟了 socket 编程，那些文档还是很有用的
And then the next part
下一部分
You'll see,we're looking only now on the server side is called bind
我们现在开始讲服务器端的 bind 函数
And
然后
What bind does then is that specific then to a server
Bind 函数是服务器上的特殊函数
And now this is a make this interfaces to the kernel
它在内核态下创建一个接口
It says I want to
它告诉内核它想要
Designate which IP address
分配哪个 IP 地址
And let me just...
让我
So I'm going to treat a little bit and let me by making sure I don't say anything that's not true
我需要再思考一下，以防我说一些错误的知识
Yeah I'm right sorry
好的，我是对的
I just want to make sure
我只是想确保这一点
Bind actually
Bind 函数实际上
Tells you
告诉你
Oh excuse me
不好意思，我漏讲了一个点
You'll see that a socket the call to socket returns an int
你们会发现 socket 函数返回了一个整形数
But it's what it's returning is a file descriptor remember we said that
它实际上是一个文件描述符，还记得我们曾经讲过
If you refer to a file a low-level file just by an integer id typically a small integer value
有一些整数，特别是一些很小的整数，是指代一些底层文件的吗
There's some standard ones for standard in,standard out,standard error
比如标准输入输出代码和标准错误代码
And then beyond that they're just assigned incrementally
这些代码递增分配
So socket will return a number
所以 socket 返回一个数
That you then refer used to refer to this as a file
你可以通过它找到一个文件
So bind then you've pass in that the name of your socket file descriptor
所以 bind 函数会调用 socket 函数返回的文件描述符
And you provide a whether is a socketaddr int
然后你需要提供一个叫 socketaddr 的整形参数
SA and I'm using the the notation
SA 这个符号
SA as a shortcut for sockaddr struct sockaddr
是 sockaddr 这个结构体的缩写
And then you have to also say what the length of the address is
之后你还需要提供地址长度
So in the case of IPv4 that would be four
IPv4 的例子中那个参数是 4
But you don't usually use that number directly there's a
一般情况下你不需要直接用到那个数字
We'll talk about it but that top-level call called gedaddr or addrinfo
我们之后会讲到一个叫做 getaddr 或是 addrinfo 的函数
As a relatively new api that was created and in this addition to the book but not in previous ones
它是一个新出现的和 socket 编程有关的 api，这是《CSAPP》最新版中新增的内容，之前的版本中没有
Become the now the standard way that you get all the parameters that you're supposed to pass into all these different calls
现在你们获得参数的标准方法应该是用各种不同函数为你们提供参数
And the idea of it then is it's a pretty small adjustment to then write code that's good for either IPv4 or IPv6
这只是一个很小的调整，但它可以使你们的程序更方便的在 IPv4 和 IPv6间切换
So you don't normally give the actual number from that you get it from another place and pass in it
所以通常你不用直接给出数字，你只需要从其它地方获取它并将其传入
So binding then
总结一下，bind 函数
It's a kernel call
是一个内核函数
That designates which particular service
它指定这个程序
This program is going to be hosting
到底要运行何种服务
Which will be the server for and that's given by its port number
这个服务器是用来干嘛的则由端口号确定
And then the next step is to
下一步是
To listen and that's just a call that says
调用 listen 函数
That will now convert this socket to a listening socket which you need as a server
它会把这个 socket 转换到监听状态，服务器需要你这么做
So it's a way of telling the kernel that this will be
这是一种告诉内核，这将作为
Will be a server side
服务器端
So obviously bind and listen are related ideas
很显然，bind 函数和 listen 函数是有关的
But you have to do both steps and in that particular order to create a listening socket or one for a server
但你必须按这个特定的顺序去执行这两步来创建一个监听 socket
And then the final part of that to operate us is to say accept
最后一个步骤是调用 accept 函数
And
然后
Oh that means okay now we've established this now I'm actually ready to receive phone calls
它表示现在我们已经创建好 socket 了，我们准备好接受一通电话了
This is essentially what it says is this is the final step to say
这基本就是它想在最后一步表达的意思
Okay this one's ready to accept connection requests
这边已经准备好接受连接请求了
It has a similar
它和
Set of arguments to socket it's socket
socket 函数有一些相同的参数
But slight difference
但有一些细微的不同
And now the interesting thing is accept will return
最有趣的是，accept 函数会返回
Yet another file descriptor
另一个文件描述符
So the first file descriptor is the sort of generic
第一个文件描述符是一般性的
Accept and base basically accept we'll
简单来说，accept 函数
Just hang there and wait until some client makes a connection
一直等待，直到有客户端和服务器建立连接
And when it does then it will set up a new socket
这时，它会新建一个 socket
And a new with a new file descriptor that then the server communicates to the client via that one
它指向一个新的文件描述符，服务器通过它于客户端通信
And I'll talk about why it's a different file descriptor in just a second
我很快会讲为什么这是两种不同的文件描述符
Okay over on the client side goes through similar steps of socket
好的，在客户端这边也有调用 socket 函数这一步
But it doesn't have to bind or listen or accept because this is a client
但没有调用 bind 函数，listen 函数或是 accept 函数的步骤，因为这是客户端
And instead what it does is it makes a call to connect
相反，它会调用一个函数去请求连接
So let me finish this off
先让我把服务器上执行的步骤写下来
So these are all on this the server side
那么这些就是服务器上执行的所有操作
And on the client side
然后在客户端上
It will make a call to connect
它会用一个函数来
From a client side is to set up a connection to server
创建一个从客户端到服务器的连接
And so
然后
Its arguments it's a little easier to understand how connect to work
这会使你更容易理解连接是如何工作的
So in particular
在个别情况下
The call to socket that was made before hand returns a file descriptor
socket 函数在文件描述符返回前就被调用了
And what this says is I want to on that particular using that particular socket
这是因为我想要用一个特定的 socket 连接
Connect to this gives a combination of an address and a port number
来连接一组特定的 IP 地址和端口号的组合
And it has to give this address length which I said like I said as before
它需要这个地址的长度，就像我之前说的
It's usually that number is filled in using the return value of of getaddrinfo
那个数字由 getaddrinfo 函数提供
But that's sort of the equivalent of pass in the call then
但这就相当于传递函数
And it returns just a code which is
它会返回一个数字
Whether the connection was successful or not
代表这个连接是否成功建立
So let me just talk about these different ports and
那么让我讲讲这些不同的端口以及
What it all means when you set up a connection
当你创建连接时它们在做什么
So when the
那么，当
The server went through bind and listen
服务器在调用 bind 函数和 listen 函数时
It created a listening port from that
它创建了一个监听端口
Which is the one that it's listening for connection requests on
用于监听是否有连接请求
And then the client when it called socket it was given a particular file descriptor for that socket
而当客户端调用 socket 函数时，它会创建一个对应那个特定 socket 连接的文件描述符
And it sends out a connection request
并发出一个连接请求
That goes out over the network
那个请求通过网络传输
And lands at the server and then the kernel hands that off to the program that's running on that particular port
最终到达服务器上，之后内核会把它交给运行在那个特定端口上的程序
And hands it off to the that call will be handled by the accept
Call to accept by the server
And then as I mentioned except actually returns a new file descriptor
Which the server will then use as its connection point to this particular client
And the theory of that is you want to be able to in general
As a server be handling multiple clients at the same time
But if I'm communicating with Google or amazon
You should be able to do so at the same time
So you want a possibility of from a single host to be able to serve multiple clients
And that's why they're all assigned different file descriptors at the server end for that particular connection
So you can think of it as the listening file descriptor is just listening for incoming requests for connections
But once it sets up a session and communicates back and forth
Those are going through different ports on the server side of things or different file descriptors I'm sorry
Same port different file descriptors
From the software that's running on the server
Okay and then during the actual communication then as I mentioned it uses reads and writes
As a way to send and receive messages
And that goes on for as long as
You know and according to whatever low level particular protocol is being supported by this application
And then
In the end then when the client the
Client is done it causes a request
And what that looks like from the server end is it tries to read from a file
And it receives an end of file a signal instead
And that tells the server okay this particular connection is gone
And so
Now it will close that particular one as this picture shows here
Potentially the server could loop back around
And accept a connection from another program and in fact
This can be done,this is what we call a serial or a internet
A serial server where can only manage one connection request at a time
And when we get later in the course and we stock talk about multi threading
We'll be able to set it up,so this thing can start accepting requests for another connection
Even while it's handling one particular client
But anyways what it will look like is the server will read
The attempt to read that we'll get an end of file it will close that particular connection
And it will go back and it will accept a new connection from a new client
Okay I'm going to jump ahead and actually start talking about some slides from
That we're if you look online they're actually from a Thursday's lecture  because
There's a lot of ground to cover in that lecture and I'd like to get a little head start
So I mentioned this
This function called get a door info which is sort of the modern way in C at least to find information about
That deals with all the funkiness of host names host addresses
All the conventions about ports and some of these various structures and things like that
And the advantage of doing it this way instead of the old way
Is first of all now it sort of unifies IPv4 and IPv6 have very similar looking interfaces
And it's fairly easy to write code that can handle either
And the other was there is problems with these old ones that they were designed in an ear before multi-threading
And so they have various statically allocated buffers
Which gave a lot of bad conditions that you had to watch out for in writing code
And we're prone to errors of various sorts
And so this new format it's actually harder to use in many levels
Because it can't hide away as many details as it used to
But it has the advantage it works better in a multi-threaded environment
The other thing that makes it hard is it's trying to be sort of the kitchen sink of protocol managers
And that makes it a little bit nasty and messy
And so we're only going to sort of focus in on the parts that we really need to make use of for this course
So in particular there's this function called getaddrinfo
Where the information you're passing is a host
Which can be either a...it's a string as it shows most these are care stars are actual real strings not fake strings
It used to be back in the old days
You use char* of generic pointer because there weren't void*
But these are actual strings
So you give the name like the domain name of a host or you can give the dotted decimal name
But written as you know sequence of characters one to eight dot so forth
A service for example that this is IPv4 TCP service
Some other information that's associated with this particular connection they refer to as hints
Because again this is trying to be a very generic looking call
And then you pass it in a pointer and it will fill in and return back a pointer to a data structure
Which is essentially the way it's returning results back to you
And then associated with that is a called free adder info that will then deallocate this space
That's used by this data structure from the result
And then there's one called getaddrinfo string error
Which lets you interpret the various error codes that get created by this routine of the value that it returns
So
Let's just look a little about this and
So the result that's returned by getaddrinfo is a link twist
Oh that is null terminated just like...most link lists are
Where it gives some combination of the name
Of this particular
Some naming information for the first top-level one is the
What I showed you the canonical name for this particular IP address
And then it gives some address information which is
You know an IPv4 them that will encode the IP address
And as a next pointer to change this link list together
And so this is actually one interesting thing about this is it sort of...
This link voice together many too many mapping potentially of of names
So if I give for example google.com
It will return a link list of all
However many or you saw with twitter it was returning about four different addresses
So this will return actually five missed entries the first will be the canonical name
And then it will give each of the four IP addresses
That's relevant at this particular time
And then you as a programmer
Then sort of walk this list you step down this list and typically
Try to use each address one after the other
And if you fail on one then you try the next and try the next until you hit the end of the list and then you say loops
Can't do it
And that goes whether you're writing a client or a server
So that addrinfo
Let's look back at what that is
Oh so
Addrinfo then is what gets returned is a list of addrinfo struct
And so the addrinfo struck contains various fields
Which talks about what type of data is here
What type of socket is it
What its canonical name is how long are its addresses you saw that it's an argument to some of the calls
A pointer to a sockaddr struct
That's the way that is encoded for IPv
What we've already seen sock adders is a sort of low-level data structure that gets used
And then an next pointer to chain the link list together
And so you'll see some of these are the arguments
That then you will use to pass into the other functions like bind and with list links and connect
And then there's another version called getnameinfo
Which you use when you've got an IP address
And you want to find what is its domain name
And because you remember that mapping is also potentially a one-to-many
There can be multiple domain names associated with it
And so it has a similar general thing
We'll just look right now it getaddrinfo
So just as an example of how you'd write code to make use of this
Essentially just as a way of probing the DNS server
Is I want to set up an argument a call to getaddrinfo
Where the string I'm going to pass the name is
Whatever I type in there to this application to main
And it just for hints just passes a bunch of zeros
And listp again these are this will just be a pointers
That I haven't actually
Oh okay so you'll notice hints is actually a struct itself
Whereas listp and *p are just listsp andp are just pointers to structs
They don't have any allocated data
So the hints I'm just going to fill in that struct with all zeros
Because I don't really need to provide any hints
I am telling it that I want an IPv6 TCP connection here
And then
So what it will do is it will return back
What returns an error code
But it will fill in returned to me a pointer
To a this link twist data structure I showed before
And now I can step through that list
Using standard linked list code and make calls to the getnameinfo function which will return back domain names
And then when it's all done I have to free up that whisk that got returned otherwise all great memory stuff
So just as a demo
What I'm
On oh host info sorry
Ah so you can think of it this is like
A not very fancy implementation of nslookup
So the kind of stuff we already saw before but let's
All it's returning are the different addresses and one of the things that I found curious is
It returns them in the same order all the time
Instead of within a slow cup it kept changing it
And I think that has to do with caching
No that changed
I know it's kind of interesting if it's
It you might want to play with this code, it's kind of you can see what's going on in different places
And so you can see though that it's
Basically getting the same kind of information
That you would from nslookup it's really just creating the DNS server to do this
But that's the start of what some of this code looks like
One of the things you
By the way when you're writing your own code,you often make use of what's called localhost
And that always just refers to the machine that you're running on it
Always has this particular IP address
So that address just refers to the machine and as a programmer
You do all your testing on one machine
You just set up both the client and the server on the same machine and play with it so
Localhost is a very useful way of doing code development
And if this shows you can request host info for others
Thanksgiving and you can also by the way
Always give a dotted decimal address
And I'm just making it up here
What and it's not very interesting because it returns back the same address
It's more interesting to run nslookup on that
So
That just gives you a sense
And as you've seen this code is pretty messy stuff to work with there's a lot of struck
So you have to initialize,you don't initialize you pass pointers
And so the code always looks a bit crufty
But that sort of the the interfaces it exists
And you'll just have to get somewhat comfortable with it
So that will do us for today then thanks